Guide to the Fox Chapel Garden Club Records, 1931-2010 AIS.2011.10
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Scrapbooks, 1958-1996; X.
  This series contains photo scrapbooks created by the club from 1958-1996. These scrapbooks contain photographs, excerpts of minutes and reports, award ribbons, and various other documents and materials. Several scrapbooks record specific events, such as club anniversaries. Of particular interest of the "Conservation" scrapbooks, which document Ruth Scott and Ruth Boyles trip as delegates of the club to an environmental summit in Washington, D.C. The series is arranged chronologically, but were received in poor condition. Large amounts of content were missing from several scrapbooks.
  - 1958-1959 (Box 11, Volume 1)
  - 1959-1960 (Box 11, Volume 2)
  - 1961-1963 (Box 11, Volume 3)
  - Conservation, 1961-1962 (Box 11, Volume 4)
  - Conservation, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Volume 5)
  - Environmental-Civic Project, 1962 (Box 11, Volume 6)
  - Community Garden Library, 1963 (Box 11, Volume 7)
  - 1970-1975 (Box 11, Volume 8)
  - 1975-1980 (Box 11, Volume 9)
  - 50th Anniversary, 1981 (Box 11, Volume 10)
  - 1981-1987 (Box 11, Volume 11)
  - 1986-1987 (Box 11, Volume 12)
  - 1988-1991 (Box 11, Volume 13)
  - 60th Anniversary, 1991 (Box 11, Volume 14)
  - 1991-1993 (Box 11, Volume 15)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 11, Volume 16)
  - 1996 (Box 11, Volume 17)
  - 1990s (Box 11, Volume 18)
- Maps, 1934-1993; XI.
  This series contains maps created for or retained by the club. The 1934 borough map was hand-drawn and colored by two members of the Fox Chapel Garden Club to accompany a smaller version found on the inside front cover of the "Things We Grow in our Kitchens" cookbook. Also of interest is the landscape design plan produced by Ezra C. Stiles for the Club. The folders are arranged chronologically.
  - Map of Fox Chapel Borough from 1934 Cookbook (Box 11, Drawer 12-6, Folder 1)
  - Landscape Design Plan by Ezra C. Stiles, 1970 (Box 11, Drawer 12-6, Folder 2)
  - Map of Fox Chapel Borough & Vicinity (2 copies), undated (Box 11, Drawer 12-6, Folder 3)
  - Map of Fox Chapel School District, 1993 (Box 11, Drawer 12-6, Folder 4)
  - Road Map of Fox Chapel Borough by Fahringer, McCarty, Grey, Inc., 1987 (Box 11, Drawer 12-6, Folder 5)
- AV Materials, 1933-2011; XII.
  This series contains audio-visual materials created or collected by the club from 1933-2011. The series is composed primarily of photographs of the clubs various activities between 1950 and the late 2000s. It also contains moving image materials (VHS and DVD recordings), and a cassette recording of songs from the club's "We Can, We Can" recycling project.
  - Photographs, 1950-2009; 1.
    The photographs in this subseries record club events from 1950-2006. A large number of photographs are undated and unlabeled, and large gaps exist between years. The photographs that were identified include the club's anniversaries and meetings, their gardening programs (flower shows, May Market, Dirt Diggers) and outreach programs (garden therapy, sneaker recycling, Trillium Trail walks). The largest number of photographs identified are from the "Pittsburgh on the Move" flower show at Harmarville Rehabilitation hospital on July 28, 1999. The series also contains photographs from the club's first garden therapy outreach program at the Veteran's Affairs hospital on Delafield Road from 1955-1960 (See Box 5, Folder 10 for the corresponding notebook entries these photographs were separated from). Where it was possible to identify photographs, they are grouped alphabetically by activity or event, and then sorted in chronological order.
    - Anniversaries & Special Events, 1981-2003
      This subgroup contains all identified photographs of club anniversaries, parties, and special events.
      - 75th Anniversary, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Christmas Auctions, 1998-2000, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - "Christmas Doorways", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - "Color Me Mine" (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Hat Parties, 1987 & 1998 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - 50th Anniverary, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Flower Shows, 1991, 1999
      This subgroup contains all identified photographs of the club's two largest flower shows, Pittsburgh in Bloom (1991) and Pittsburgh on the Move (1999).
      - Pittsburgh in Bloom, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Pittsburgh in Bloom, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Pittsburgh in Bloom- Single Blooms, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Pittsburgh in Bloom- flower show manual (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- set-up and preparation (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- signage, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- awards, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- FCGC members, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- individual blooms #1, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- individual blooms #2, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- vegetables, close-Ups, awards, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- arrangements #1, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- arrangments #2, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Pittsburgh on the Move- flower show manual (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Garden Club Events, 1994-2009
      This subgroup contains all identified photographs related to monthly and annual club events.
      - Cookbook cover photos, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - "Dirt Diggers", 1998, 2000, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Garden Market / May Market, 1991, 1993, 2000-2001, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Seed Gathering, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Summer Garden Tour, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Workshops, 1999-2000, 2004 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Meetings, 1998-2003
      This subgroup contains all identified photographs taken at regular club meetings, including photographs of guest speakers.
      - Meetings, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 27)
      - Meetings, 1999-2003 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Meetings, undated/unidentified (Box 7, Folder 29)
      - Meetings, speakers, 1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Outreach Projects, 1955-2005
      This subgroup contains all identified photographs of club community service and outreach projects. Folders are arranged alphabetically by topic.
      - Earth Day/Environmental Education, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 31)
      - Garden Therapy at VA Hospital, 1955-1960 (Box 7, Folder 32)
      - Outdoor Therapy Garden, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 33)
      - Outdoor Therapy Garden, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 34)
      - Outdoor Therapy Garden, 2000, 2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Sneaker Recycling, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Trillium Trail, 1958-1994 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Unidentified / Negatives
      This subgroup contains all photographs that were not identified in the collection, as well as photo negatives. They are separated into photographs of unidentified persons and undidentified events or locations.
      - Persons, Club Members (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Flowers / Gardens (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Negatives (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Moving Images, 1987-2001; 2.
    The VHS tapes and DVD in this subseries are recordings of club events and special projects. In particular, the subseries contains two copies of a documentary the club commissioned and recorded in 2001 about its two most famous members, Ruth Dye Boyles and Ruth Jury Scott. There are also recordings of one of the club's "Hat Parties," and a recording from their garden therapy work at Harmarville Rehabilitation Hospital.
    - Fox Chapel Garden Club "Hat Party" (DVD), July 29, 1987 (Box 8, Item 1)
    - Fox Chapel Garden Club "Hat Party" (VHS), July 24, 1987 (Box 8, Item 2)
    - "Gardening at Harmarville" (VHS), October 1990 (Box 8, Item 3)
    - "Ruth Boyles and Ruth Scott: How They Changed Our Lives," (VHS, c. 1), 2001 (Box 8, Item 4)
    - "Ruth Boyles and Ruth Scott: How They Changed Our Lives," (VHS, c. 2), 2001 (Box 8, Item 5)
  - Audio Cassette, 1989; 3.
    The tape in this subseries is a recording of songs written by the Club as a part of its recycling outreach in the community. The songs are sung by a kindergarten class, and are related to materials housed in the Project Files series (See Box 4, Folder 14).
    - "We Can, We Can" (Box 8, Item 6)
- Artifacts, undated; XIII.
  This series contains several artifacts related to the club. The primary object is a dress smock said to have been worn by Ruth D. Boyles every year during the May Market. The series also includes club signage from flower shows and the "Fox Head" logo of the club. The materials are undated.
  - Ruth Boyle's dress smock from May Market (Box 9, Item 1)
  - FCGC Signage (Box 9, Item 2)